Guide to the Donald Ray papers, 1938-1992 MS0155.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Donald Ray papers
1938-1992
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Donald P. Ray
MS0155.UA
6 Linear Feet
Donald Ray received his Master of Arts degree in 1947 from The George Washington University, and served as Director of the National Institute of Social and Behavioral Sciences. Collection includes correspondence, reports, articles, pamphlets and books.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Papers were donated to the University Archives in 1992.
Biographical Note
Donald Ray received his Master of Arts degree in 1947 from The George Washington University, and served as Director of the National Institute of Social and Behavioral Sciences.
This note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Collection consists of Dr. Donald Ray's papers, books, magazines, pamphlets, and correspondence as the Director of the National Institute of Social and Behavioral Sciences (which not officially connected with GW but Dr. Ray did use office space and a mailing address at the university.) The materials range in date from 1938-92.
Dr. Ray corresponded with companies such as Kodak, U.S. Steel, American Express and Beneficial Management, asking for financial support for The Institute of Social and Behavioral Sciences. Other correspondence deals with the yearly symposiums of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), which published papers by leading professionals in the social sciences field; as well as letters from the White House, Congress, Senate, and Ronald Reagan concerning U.S. policy toward China and Vietnam.
Collection Organization
Organized in one series.
Collection note
Formerly ACC#155
United States; Asia; United States. Congress; University of Georgia; Reagan, Ronald; United States Steel Corporation; Donald P. Ray; Duke University; George Washington University; American Association for the Advancement of Science; Columbia University
- Books: Annual Report on Administration of Tyosen 1937-1938. Keizyo., 12/1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Books: Answering Questions on Manchuria. Tokyo, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Books: Hall, Ray Ovid. Chapters and Documents on Chinese National Banking. Shanghai: Commercial Press, Shanghai Limited, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Books: Hearn, Lafcadio. Japan An Interpretation. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Books: Income and Franchise Tax Law and Regulations. Washington, D.C., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Books: Japanese Drama. Tokyo, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Books: Japan Information for Visitors 1938. Thomas Cook. London (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Books: Marshall, Alfred. Principals of Economics. New York: The Macmillan Company, 8th ed., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Books: Ray, Donald, ed. Trends in Social Science. New York: Philosophical Library, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Books: Sellin, Thorsten, ed. The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science. Philadelphia: The American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Books: Swisher, Earl. China's Management of the American Barbarians, A Study of Sino-American Relations 1841-1861, with Documents. New Haven, Conn.: Far Eastern Publications, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Books: Yanaga, Chitoshi. Japan since Perry. New York: McGraw Hill Book Company, Inc., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Magazines: Fortune. Japan, April, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Magazines: Nippon. Tokyo, Japan, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Magazines: Nippon Today and Tomorrow. Japan, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Magazines: Orient: The Pictorial Asahigraph Overseas Edition. Vol. 8, No. 4. Japan, 08/1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Index cards with notes written on them, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Solicitor's information cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Stamps for the National Institute of Social & Behavioral Sciences, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Article: Funding of Social Science Research, Paper: Economic Conditions in Japan, 06/1938 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Articles: The Logistic Law in Communication 1961, The Economy of USSR, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Certificates of Registration for D.C. Charitable Solicitation Act, Correspondence, 1959-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Committee on Foreign Affairs text, abstract, correspondence, American Security Council Washington Report papers, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Compilation of social science articles Research Perspectives in Social Science, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Congressional record proceedings, a bill, newspaper, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, articles, notes, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1966-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, abstracts, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, abstracts, notes, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, abstracts, paper: Plan and Market a Look at the Economic Reforms in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence; article on Japan; economic and financial reports from Manufacturers Hanover Trust; Economic Outlook USA 1975 Forecast Issue; The Austrian Economics Newsletter vol. 2. no. 3 Spring 1980, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence; articles; bulletins: A Current Appraisal of the Behavioral Sciences; notes; pamphlets: National Support for Behavioral Science, Strengthening the Behavioral Sciences, The Voice of America Forum Lectures Introduction to the Behavioral Sciences, 1958-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence from the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace and from Congress, Senate, White House; articles; notes; newspaper clippings, 1985-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence; forms such as the AAAS Annual Meeting advance registration form; schedule of sessions for AAAS in 1970; Newsletter of the American Anthropological Association; notes; copy presentation guide; author index cards, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, invoices, receipts, remittance statements, purchase order forms, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, invoices, receipts, purchase order forms, remittance statements, 1959-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence from Duke University, Columbia University, and the University of Georgia; newspaper clippings on U.S policy on China, Taiwan, and UN; journal article: Conditions Favoring Major Advances in Social Science, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence: White House, Senate, Congress, House of Delegates from Virginia, and Class of '35 South High School 40th Anniversary Reunion; journal articles: Does the Past have Useful Economics? Buchanan on Political Economy A Review Article, Tariffs and Other Measures of Trade Control: A Survey of Recent Developments; notes; book reviews, 1963-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, letterhead, notes, federal register, journal articles, invitations, financial statements, constitution, certificate of incorporation: All relating to the National Institute of Social & Behavioral Sciences, 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, letters papers: A New Look at the Stagnation Thesis, The Japanese Communists and the Sino-Soviet Dispute, and Authoritarianism: Transitional Democracy in Asian States, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, misc., notice of proposed rule making, pamphlets, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, newspaper clipping, article, abstracts, notes, index cards, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, notes, newspaper clippings, Donald Ray's H.S. diploma, 1935-1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence, notes, letterhead, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Correspondence, pamphlet, notes, newspaper clippings, forms, annual report for charitable organizations, map, letters from Reagan, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Correspondence papers, 1952-1957 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence papers, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Correspondence papers, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence papers, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Correspondence papers, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence papers, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Correspondence papers, newspaper clippings, article, 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence papers, newspaper clippings, 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Correspondence papers, newspaper clippings, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Correspondence papers, newspaper clipping, abstracts, journal articles, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence papers, notes, 1958-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, program, news clipping, 1955-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, vitas, abstracts, notes papers, AAAS, registration form, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, vouchers, invoices, receipts, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Correspondence from the White House and Congress, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence from the White House, Senate, and GWU; notes; newspaper clippings, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Financial statements for the National Institute of Social & Behavioral Science, correspondence, forms, notices, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- The George Washington University Bulletin (pictorial issue), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Income tax forms, exemption forms, correspondence, 1960-1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Japan: newspaper clippings, articles, list of Japan's government and army papers, ninth conference of the institute of public relations report, Japanese magazine, 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- The Lambert Distance Table, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Newsletter, AAAS pamphlet, fundraising guide pamphlet, correspondence, abstract, grant pamphlets, notes, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Newspaper clippings on Vietnam and China, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Newspaper clippings on US involvement in Vietnam and China, 1973-1984 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Newspaper clippings, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Notes and paper: British-Japanese Competition for China Market, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Notes on business cycle, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Notes on Economics 201, 202, 213, 224, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Notes on mercantilism, foreign exchange definition, outline papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Notes on natural science and partial equilibrium theory, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Notes on papers such as, UN Bank for Reconstruction and Development, The International Monetary Fund, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Notes about the Social Sciences, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Notes on tariffs and commercial treaties papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Pamphlets: The Galley, Harvard Club of Washington, D.C., Amerasia, An Atlas of the War, The Work of the Asia Foundation, Japan A Close-Up, 1937-1956 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Pamphlets: India and the War, Political Advance in India, India, American Economic Review, S.M.R., Digest of the Civil Air Regulations for Student and Private Pilots, Primary Ground Study Manual, 1939-1946 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Pamphlets: The United States in the World Economy, Flight Instructor's Manual, Cosmos Club, 1939-1953 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Pamphlets: Social Science Oct. 1950 and Jan. 1949, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Pamphlets: Social Science Oct. 1952, June 1951, and June 1950, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Pamphlets: Social Science Oct. 1953, Oct. 1954, Oct. 1955, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Pamphlets: Social Science Oct. 1959, Jan. 1960, April 1960, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Pamphlets: Social Science June 1960, Oct. 1960, April 1961, 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Paper, articles, newsletter, notes, forms, 1963-1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Papers, notes, journal article, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Pearl Harbor news clippings, map, journal articles, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Research, articles, pamphlets, correspondence, bulletin, 1959-1966 (Box 4, Folder 18)